<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://ferrispnugraha.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://ferrispnugraha.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2024-10-25T17:45:09+00:00</updated><id>https://ferrispnugraha.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>A simple, whitespace theme for academics. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Practice lists for IPhO, APhO, etc.</title><link href="https://ferrispnugraha.github.io/blog/2023/olympiad-practice/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Practice lists for IPhO, APhO, etc."/><published>2023-09-04T13:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-09-04T13:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://ferrispnugraha.github.io/blog/2023/olympiad-practice</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ferrispnugraha.github.io/blog/2023/olympiad-practice/"><![CDATA[<p>The following list is not exhaustive, and it is not meant to be. It is just a list of books that I have read and found useful. I hope it can be useful for you too. The key is to practice with available problems and solutions.</p> <h4 id="general-physics">General physics</h4> <hr/> <p>D. Halliday, R. Resnick, and J. Walker, Fundamentals of Physics. Milton: John Wiley, 2020.</p> <h4 id="olympiads">Olympiads</h4> <hr/> <p>H. Kwee, T. J. Anly, and Y. Virgus, Menjadi Juara Olimpiade. Edisi kedua. Yayasan Sinergi Mencerdaskan Tunas Negeri, 2017.</p> <p>L. Holics, 300 Creative Physics Problems: With Solutions. London: Anthem Press, 2011.</p> <p>J. Kalda. <a href="https://www.ioc.ee/~kalda/ipho/">Study guides for IPhO</a></p> <p>For IPhO and APhO, may refer to the official websites or at <a href="https://ipho.olimpicos.net/">here</a> and <a href="https://apho.olimpicos.net/">here</a></p> <h4 id="classical-mechanics-and-waves">Classical mechanics and Waves</h4> <hr/> <p>D. Morin, Introduction to Classical Mechanics: With Problems and Solutions. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press, 2019.</p> <p>Y.-K. Lim, Problems and Solutions on Mechanics. Singapore: World Scientific, 2008.</p> <p>H. J. Pain, The Physics of Vibrations and Waves. Chichester: Wiley, 2008.</p> <p>H. Georgi, The Physics of Waves. Englewood Cliffs, NJ: Prentice Hall, 2022.</p> <p>J. Wang and B. Ricardo, Competitive Physics: Mechanics and Waves. World Scientific, 2019.</p> <h4 id="electromagnetism">Electromagnetism</h4> <hr/> <p>D. J. Griffiths, Introduction to Electrodynamics. Cambridge University Press, 2023.</p> <p>Y. Lim and S. Zhao, Problems and Solutions on Electromagnetism. Singapore: World Scientific, 2007.</p> <p>E. M. Purcell and D. J. Morin, Electricity and Magnetism. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press, 2013.</p> <p>J. Wang and B. Ricardo, Competitive Physics: Thermodynamics, Electromagnetism and Relativity. Singapore: World Scientific Publishing Co. Pte. Ltd., 2019.</p> <h4 id="optics">Optics</h4> <hr/> <p>E. Hecht, Optics. Boston: Pearson, 2016.</p> <p>Z. Abidin, Gelombang dan Optik. STKIP Surya, 2017.</p> <p>G. Bai, G. Guo, and Y. Lim, Problems and Solutions on Optics. Singapore: World Scientific, 2011.</p> <h4 id="thermodynamics">Thermodynamics</h4> <hr/> <p>F. W. Sears and G. L. Salinger, Thermodynamics, Kinetic Theory, and Statistical Thermodynamics. Reading, MA: Addison-Wesley, 1986.</p> <p>S. Blundell and K. M. Blundell, Concepts in Thermal Physics. Oxford: Oxford University Press, 2019.</p> <p>Y. Lim, Problems and Solutions on Thermodynamics and Statistical Mechanics. Singapore: World Scientific, 1996.</p> <h4 id="relativity">Relativity</h4> <hr/> <p>D. Morin, Introduction to Classical Mechanics: With Problems and Solutions. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press, 2019.</p> <p>Y. Lim, Problems and Solutions on Solid State Physics, Relativity and Miscellaneous Topics. Singapore: World Scientific, 1994.</p> <h4 id="modern-physics">Modern physics</h4> <hr/> <p>K. S. Krane, Modern Physics. Hoboken, NJ: Wiley, 2020.</p> <p>C. Kittel and P. McEuen, Introduction to Solid State Physics. Hoboken, NJ: Wiley, 2022.</p> <p>D. J. Griffiths and D. F. Schroeter, Introduction to Quantum Mechanics. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press, 2020.</p> <p>Y. Lim, Problems and Solutions on Quantum Mechanics. Singapore: World Scientific, 1994.</p> <p>Y. Lim, Problems and Solutions on Atomic, Nuclear, and Particle Physics. Singapore: World Scientific, 2000.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="reading"/><category term="physics"/><category term="olympiad"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[classical mechanics, electromagnetism, thermodynamics, optics, wave, relativity, and modern physics]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Reading lists for superconducting quantum computer hardware</title><link href="https://ferrispnugraha.github.io/blog/2023/quantum-computing-hardware/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Reading lists for superconducting quantum computer hardware"/><published>2023-08-29T10:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-29T10:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://ferrispnugraha.github.io/blog/2023/quantum-computing-hardware</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ferrispnugraha.github.io/blog/2023/quantum-computing-hardware/"><![CDATA[<p>Coming soon!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="reading"/><category term="physics"/><category term="superconducting"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[how CPB developed into a zoo of superconducting qubits we know today]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Reading lists for circuit quantum electrodynamics</title><link href="https://ferrispnugraha.github.io/blog/2023/cqed-reading-lists/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Reading lists for circuit quantum electrodynamics"/><published>2023-08-29T09:58:16+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-29T09:58:16+00:00</updated><id>https://ferrispnugraha.github.io/blog/2023/cqed-reading-lists</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ferrispnugraha.github.io/blog/2023/cqed-reading-lists/"><![CDATA[<p>Coming soon!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="reading"/><category term="cqed"/><category term="engineering"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[from lumped elements to distributed]]></summary></entry></feed>